+91 8670300541 Bengaluru, Karnataka naveenkumarsangi@pm.me

Naveen Kumar

Software Development Engineer III

GitHub: nkprince007 LinkedIn: naveenkumarsangi Website: naveenkumarsangi.me

7+ years of owning, designing and delivering engineering solutions at multiple organisations in fast-paced multi-cloud and on-premise environments. Certified DevOps Engineer with proven experience in Kubernetes, Serverless and Managed Services from cloud providers like Azure, GCP and AWS.

SKILLS

Tools Docker, Kubernetes, Helm, Vagrant, Terraform **Monitoring** Grafana + Prometheus + Loki, PMM, Kiali

Ingress / Routing NGINX, Kong, Istio

Scripting Ansible, Chef, Bash, Python

Backend Frameworks echo, gin (golang), Django, Flask, Node.js
Frontend / Mobile React, Angular, Vue, SvelteKit, Flutter, Cordova

Languages Python, Go, Bash, JS/TS, C/C++, Dart

Datastores Postgres+postgis, TimescaleDB, MongoDB, Redis

Schedulers Celery, RabbitMQ

EXPERIENCE

ColorTokens Inc. - Xcloud & Xshield NextGen teams (Cyber Security)

Bengaluru, India

July 2022 — Current

Member of Technical Staff - III (DevOps & Backend)

- Developed custom kubernetes operator to facilitate multiple Short Lived Application Testing Environments on single cluster with support for ephermeral databases using istio.
- Building hardened docker images (based on IronBank) for enhanced security.
- Converting monolith services running on AWS EC2 and AWS Lambda into kubernetes microservices.
- Deploying and managing secure, on-premise, air-gapped kubernetes clusters on vSphere and AWS for various clients.
- Integrating secrets and confidential data management with key-rotation support using Hashicorp Vault.
- Configuring traffic patterns using kong and istio.
- Setting up modular terraform for multi-region cluster and microservices deployment in on Azure and AWS
- Setting up CI/CD pipelines on AWS Codebuild, Jenkins & Azure DevOps.
- Experience using multiple AWS/Azure cloud services like EKS/AKS, S3/Azblob, VPC/VNET, EC2/VM, ELB, IAM, SES, CloudWatch etc.
- Developed Zero-Trust security analysis workflow on kubernetes clusters for CSPM on AKS, EKS, GKE platforms.
- Developed DHCP relay server to perform network micro-segmentation.

Auguan Ltd. (Finance Sector)

Sr. Full-Stack Engineer

Bengaluru, India (Part-time)

May 2021 — July 2021

- · Building data pipelines for financial news collection from several search engines
- Redesigned interface for complex graph visualizations between entities
- Maintaining and deploying data pipelines to AWS ECS

Viper Development UG [now FounderBlocks] (Multiple sectors)

Sr. Full-Stack Engineer

Hamburg, Germany

July 2018 — June 2022

Skynet MCANISM (Ad-tracking platform)

- Improved API response times by 20 times on report generation pipelines
- Reduced database clutter with flat hypertables using time-partitioning on TimescaleDB
- Designed a reusable filtering architecture in django for report generation
- Managed container orchestration using kubernetes and deploying final applications on GCP
- Actively participated in data recovery, production release monitoring, rollback and debugging k8s microservices on GCP
- Worked on scripts for CI/CD pipelines, database snapshots, blob storage backups and access key rotation

Pandas ZF (Human Machine Interfaces)

- Developed a real-time IOT focused web application to collect telematics information from automobile suspension kits
- Extended the real-time data platform to provide historical ride quality information on selected roads

myndpaar.de (Mental Health / Counselling)

- Wire-framing and building a cross platform mobile application for couples counseling in association with myndwerk GmbH
- Engaging users to perform various activities using automated push notifications
- Added in-app payments support for monthly subscriptions

GitMate UG (Developer tools)

Hamburg, Germany (Part-time)

Full-Stack Engineer / Developer Tools

Dec 2016 — July 2018

- · Helped in building a multilingual code linter that supports multiple languages using a single config file
- Built a linting and codesmell detection pipeline from scratch to manage continuous integration for several customers
- Designed an open-source reusable plugin architecture to link the linting pipeline to several cloud based Git-hosting services
- Worked on a duplicate issue detection plugin to identify closely matching issues on GitHub projects

Wipro Business Solutions (Internship)

Bengaluru, India

Software Engineering Intern

May 2017 — June 2017

- Designed a native Android application to manage ONVIF compliant cameras
- Added Android Auto support to connect with rear parking cameras in automobiles

Education	
Master of Sciences, CS — University of Illinois, Chicago Bachelor of Technology, CSE — National Institute of Technology, Durgapur	2019 — 2021 2014 — 2018
Credentials	
Certified Kubernetes Application Developer — Cloud Native Compute Foundation	Dec 2023
Honors & Awards	
Mozilla Open Source Support Awardee — Mozilla Google Summer of Code Contributor — coala	2018 2017
EXTRA-CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES	
Mentor, Google Summer of Code — coala Mentor, Google Code-In — coala Mentor, Google Code-In — coala Mentor, Winter of Code — IIT Kharagpur	2018 2018 2017 2017
Open Source Workshops at NIT Durgapur: Admin & Mentor	2016 — 2017